<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-05-02T18:12:07+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Code for Nepal</title><subtitle>Community of volunteers helping address Nepal's challenges using civic tech to innovate, organize and advocate digital literacy</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Donate to save lives and help Nepalis fight COVID-19 Pandemic</title><link href="/2021/05/02/donate-to-save-lives-and-help-nepalis-fight-COVID-19-pandemic.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Donate to save lives and help Nepalis fight COVID-19 Pandemic" /><published>2021-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2021/05/02/donate-to-save-lives-and-help-nepalis-fight-COVID-19-pandemic</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2021/05/02/donate-to-save-lives-and-help-nepalis-fight-COVID-19-pandemic.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://unsdg.un.org/sites/default/files/2020-07/nepal_covid_july2020_960x640.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why&quot;&gt;Why&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nepal has run out of hospital beds due to rapidly rising COVID-19 cases. The Health Ministry has said that the situation is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/01/world/nepal-india-covid.html&quot;&gt;“unmanageable”&lt;/a&gt;. Just a few weeks ago, Nepal was recording fewer than 100 cases a day. On May 1, it recorded over 7,000 COVID-19 cases. Data suggests Nepal currently has one of the highest positivity rates in the world and is on track to double its COVID cases every five days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This fundraiser is intended to help bring much needed resources and potentially help run a vacant hospital temporarily in Kathmandu that will provide upto &lt;strong&gt;300 general ward beds and 35 ICU beds.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our goal is to raise &lt;strong&gt;USD 15,000&lt;/strong&gt;. All your donations are tax deductible in the US. We also encourage you to speak with your employer to explore the possibility of employer matching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-donate&quot;&gt;How to Donate&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/donate/517821549237041/&quot;&gt;FACEBOOK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.paypal.com/donate?hosted_button_id=95R9GEGDABKK2&quot;&gt;PAYPAL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;form action=&quot;https://www.paypal.com/donate&quot; method=&quot;post&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot; style=&quot;margin-bottom:2rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;input type=&quot;hidden&quot; name=&quot;hosted_button_id&quot; value=&quot;95R9GEGDABKK2&quot; /&gt;
&lt;input type=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://www.paypalobjects.com/en_US/i/btn/btn_donateCC_LG.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; name=&quot;submit&quot; title=&quot;PayPal - The safer, easier way to pay online!&quot; alt=&quot;Donate with PayPal button&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;https://www.paypal.com/en_US/i/scr/pixel.gif&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;implementation-and-transparency&quot;&gt;Implementation and transparency&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will publish complete details of donations every 15 days on our website: &lt;a href=&quot;https://codefornepal.org&quot;&gt;https://codefornepal.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Details and cost of every single item procured through this fundraiser will be published via our website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use of fund
We are partnering with &lt;a href=&quot;http://samarthanepal.org/&quot;&gt;Samartha Nepal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://janataclinic.org/&quot;&gt;Janata clinic&lt;/a&gt; and other local groups to provide resources to help operationalize the facility for CoViD isolation and ICU wards for critical patients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are also working to support families who have lost their sole breadwinners and are on the brink of poverty. At this rate, it is very likely that there will be scores of families without a source of income and in need of basic supplies to survive on a daily basis within and outside of Kathmandu Valley. With our network of partners all over the country, especially in the Southern border of Nepal that is being hit terribly, we aim to expand our support.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Code for Nepal</name></author><category term="highlight" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How DataCamp is helping me learn data science</title><link href="/2021/04/11/datacamp-experience.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How DataCamp is helping me learn data science" /><published>2021-04-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-04-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2021/04/11/datacamp-experience</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2021/04/11/datacamp-experience.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://codefornepal.org/data-fellowship/assets/og-image.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Launching a Fellowship program to build data skills of over 500 Nepalis globally&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In college, I am planning to study computer science and economics. However, I did not want to wait to learn the basics of data science till I got to college. In that sense, Datacamp has truly helped me overcome the barriers of time and space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got access to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.datacamp.com/&quot;&gt;DataCamp&lt;/a&gt; as a member of Code for Nepal, a non-profit organization working to increase digital literacy and data literacy in Nepal. DataCamp as part of its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.datacamp.com/community/blog/datacamp-donates-50-partners&quot;&gt;global effort&lt;/a&gt; to build data skills donated thousands of subscriptions to organizations and schools globally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I worked to enhance the learning experiences of 100s of others who were selected as Code for Nepal’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://codefornepal.org/2021/02/14/launching-a-fellowship-program-to-build-data-skills-of-over-500-nepalis-globally&quot;&gt;Data Fellows&lt;/a&gt;, I was increasing my own knowledge of data science and familiarity with DataCamp. The courses on datacamp are developed to meet the expectations of learners at every level including one like myself. I have realized that to ensure the quality of learning and include the needs of different types of learners, tools like podcasts, hints, assessments have been developed. I have found them very helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, students can rate the courses and give feedback about their learning experience to DataCamp which helps improve the courses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had no prior experience with programming languages. I knew a little bit of HTML and Q-basic that I had learned in middle school. As a total beginner at the start of my datacamp journey, I discovered ‘Introduction to python’, “Introduction to R”, and “Introduction to SQL, are free courses on Datacamp and they were the perfect place to start. After I finished these free courses I took a skilled assessment which recommended me to learn Python.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step in my journey was to start my first lesson on DataCamp. This is where I had to decide to make a decision of whether I wanted to start with an individual course or a track. The courses started with very basic: types, variables, basic calculations. Therefore even as a beginner that has never written or read a single line of code, I was able to follow the material presented very easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The courses on DataCamp take place on your browser so you don’t have to download anything to learn. I am very impressed with the concept of interactive e-learning with DataCamp as it allowed me to become active with my own learning experience. Interestingly Datacamp XP is a symbolic point-system that rewards learners like me for engaging in learning. XP is awarded to learners for progressing in courses, exercises, and projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I use hints or show answer methods for solving problems a certain amount of my XP was used which motivated me to try and solve problems on my own as I did not want to lose the hard-earned XP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Datacamp also has a section dedicated to getting real-life experience with projects. I have some courses bookmarked so that I know what I have next on my list to achieve and I can revise by taking assessments that are already there on datacamp for me. On the live events tab, there are always upcoming events which has webinars and live training sessions to learn about data-driven organizations. I am thrilled to learn new things every day and datacamp feels like a roadmap where I am on a data car that leads me safely by minimizing risk and providing clarity to reach my destination as a data scientist. This journey has to be my favorite of all time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, let me share that when I finished my first-course introduction to python I was very proud of myself. After all, I managed to accomplish a significant step towards eventually becoming a data expert. I realized that becoming data fluent would require more time and dedication. I look forward to completing more courses, tracks, and projects that DataCamp has to offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may be the fact that all our fellows at DataCamp have a positive experience with different courses like python, R, SQL, and Machine learning. In the era of the COVID-19 pandemic, as a high school student, I realized it is necessary to reinforce the various learning Opportunities that prioritizes strengthening my data skills and DataCamp was the best platform for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the coming weeks, I will share how others in our community are using DataCamp. In the meantime, I would be curious to hear about your experience in coding. Please share your experiences or thoughts in the comment section below.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Anshu Adhikari</name></author><category term="highlight" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Launching a Fellowship program to build data skills of over 500 Nepalis globally</title><link href="/2021/02/14/launching-a-fellowship-program-to-build-data-skills-of-over-500-nepalis-globally.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Launching a Fellowship program to build data skills of over 500 Nepalis globally" /><published>2021-02-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-02-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2021/02/14/launching-a-fellowship-program-to-build-data-skills-of-over-500-nepalis-globally</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2021/02/14/launching-a-fellowship-program-to-build-data-skills-of-over-500-nepalis-globally.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://codefornepal.org/data-fellowship/assets/og-image.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Launching a Fellowship program to build data skills of over 500 Nepalis globally&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are excited to launch &lt;a href=&quot;https://codefornepal.org/data-fellowship/&quot;&gt;Data Fellowship&lt;/a&gt; to build the data skills of over 500 Nepalis. There are only two criteria to apply for this fellowship. First, applicants must be able to commit at least 5-10 hours per week for the first 2-3 months. Second, they should be curious and interested in learning new skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Applicants can be based anywhere. They can come from any background. They can be students, professionals, or unemployed. We highly encourage women and especially people from provinces 2 and 6 to apply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a world where everything is digitized, data skills have become critical. The ability to find, analyze and use data can not only help one do well professionally but also lead a more meaningful life. During this historic and tragic pandemic, we have been seen how people and businesses that are digitally connected and data-savvy can withstand the crisis compared to those who are not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any Nepali who is keen on making progress personally, professionally, or tackling a challenge in their community will benefit from this fellowship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This fellowship provides a safe and convenient opportunity for Nepalis to gain new skills. Those who have access to the Internet and a laptop can take courses at their own convenience and earn certificates. The Fellows will also have the opportunity to virtually contribute to civic technology and open data products such as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://opendatanepal.com/&quot;&gt;Open Data Nepal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nepalmap.org/&quot;&gt;NepalMap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://asknepal.info/&quot;&gt;AskNepal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sangraha.org/&quot;&gt;Sangraha&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The total monetary value of the program is over USD 200,000 or 2 crore Nepali rupees. This fellowship would not have been possible without the generous support of &lt;a href=&quot;https://datacamp.com&quot;&gt;DataCamp&lt;/a&gt;, a leader in building the data skills of people around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open Knowledge Nepal and Code for Nepal have partnered to offer support for career opportunities and mentorship to Fellows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Selected Fellows can choose to take classes from DataCamp experts at their own convenience to become Data Scientists, Data Engineers, Data Analysts, or Quantitative Analysts. If a Fellow has completed a certain career track and is interested in learning more skills from DataCamp, we would be keen to support that as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We welcome you to apply and help us spread the word.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>RaviNepal</name></author><category term="highlight" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cumulative number of confirmed COVID-19 cases in Nepal has increased dramatically’</title><link href="/2020/11/21/cumulative-number-of-confirmed-cases.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cumulative number of confirmed COVID-19 cases in Nepal has increased dramatically’" /><published>2020-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2020/11/21/cumulative-number-of-confirmed-cases</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020/11/21/cumulative-number-of-confirmed-cases.html">&lt;p&gt;Just 6 months ago, Nepal had just 1,500 confirmed cases of COVID-19 in Nepal. Since then the number of confirmed cases has increased dramatically in the country. Globally, experts are warning that during winter COVID-19 cases will likely rise as gatherings move indoors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dataviz:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://ourworldindata.org/coronavirus-data-explorer?zoomToSelection=true&amp;amp;country=~NPL&amp;amp;region=World&amp;amp;casesMetric=true&amp;amp;interval=total&amp;amp;hideControls=true&amp;amp;smoothing=0&amp;amp;pickerMetric=location&amp;amp;pickerSort=asc&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; height: 600px; border: 0px none;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>codefornepal</name></author><category term="highlight" /><summary type="html">Just 6 months ago, Nepal had just 1,500 confirmed cases of COVID-19 in Nepal. Since then the number of confirmed cases has increased dramatically in the country. Globally, experts are warning that during winter COVID-19 cases will likely rise as gatherings move indoors.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Google data now shows fewer people in Nepal are staying indoors amid the Coronavirus pandemic</title><link href="/2020/05/google-data-now-shows-fewer-people-in-nepal-are-staying-indoors-amid-the-coronavirus-pandemic/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Google data now shows fewer people in Nepal are staying indoors amid the Coronavirus pandemic" /><published>2020-05-19T21:48:29+00:00</published><updated>2020-05-19T21:48:29+00:00</updated><id>/2020/05/google-data-now-shows-fewer-people-in-nepal-are-staying-indoors-amid-the-coronavirus-pandemic</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020/05/google-data-now-shows-fewer-people-in-nepal-are-staying-indoors-amid-the-coronavirus-pandemic/">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://covid19.gov.np/&quot;&gt;Government of Nepal&lt;/a&gt; has reported over 350 COVID-19 positive cases and two deaths due to this novel coronavirus as of this writing. To prevent the mass spread, Nepal has been under a national lockdown since March 24.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In late March, Google released its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/covid19/mobility/&quot;&gt;COVID-19 Community Mobility Report&lt;/a&gt; to help users “understand responses to social distancing guidance related to COVID-19.” Code for Nepal compared Google’s reports from March 29 and May 9 and found fewer people in Nepal are staying indoors amid the coronavirus pandemic. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mobility trends for places categorized as “retail and recreation” or places such as restaurants, shopping centers, or movie theatres on March 29 decreased sharply (-78%) compared to February 16. Mobility trends for places categorized as “grocery and pharmacy” or places such as grocery markets, food shops, or pharmacies decreased by 69%. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost six weeks later, on May 9, mobility trends to “retail and recreation” have increased by 11% compared to the March 29 trend. And mobility trends for “grocery and pharmacy” have increased by 17%. Similarly, mobility trends for workplaces increased by 37%. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For details, check out this chart. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important to note that this data is not representative of all Nepalis. According to Google, “insights in these reports are created with aggregated, anonymized sets of data from users who have turned on Google’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/3118687&quot;&gt;Location History setting&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We welcome your thoughts and comments below.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>codefornepal</name></author><category term="Code For Nepal" /><category term="dataviz" /><category term="General" /><category term="dataviz" /><category term="nepal" /><category term="highlight" /><summary type="html">The Government of Nepal has reported over 350 COVID-19 positive cases and two deaths due to this novel coronavirus as of this writing. To prevent the mass spread, Nepal has been under a national lockdown since March 24.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">You are a young woman and want to excel in the tech market in Nepal? Apply for this fellowship by March 19</title><link href="/2020/03/fellowship-by-march-19/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="You are a young woman and want to excel in the tech market in Nepal? Apply for this fellowship by March 19" /><published>2020-03-07T17:13:43+00:00</published><updated>2020-03-07T17:13:43+00:00</updated><id>/2020/03/fellowship-by-march-19</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020/03/fellowship-by-march-19/">&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-large&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://codefornepal.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Hawkins_fellows_2019-1024x768.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-2518&quot; srcset=&quot;https://codefornepal.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Hawkins_fellows_2019-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://codefornepal.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Hawkins_fellows_2019-300x225.jpg 300w, https://codefornepal.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Hawkins_fellows_2019-768x576.jpg 768w, https://codefornepal.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Hawkins_fellows_2019.jpg 1440w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Hawkins Fellows from the class of 2019.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that applications are open for the 2nd batch of &lt;a href=&quot;https://codefornepal.org/2019/03/hawkins-fellowship/&quot;&gt;Hawkins Fellows&lt;/a&gt;. The objective of the 12-week fellowship program organized by Code for Nepal in partnership with &lt;a href=&quot;https://insightworkshop.io/&quot;&gt;Insight Workshop&lt;/a&gt; is to help increase female talent in the technology job market in Nepal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(This is a rolling application process which works on a “first come first served basis”. The sooner you apply, you have a higher chance of being accepted.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;about-the-fellowship-program&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About the fellowship program&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Hawkins Fellowship by Code for Nepal in partnership with Insight Workshop Academy includes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A. A twelve-week program at the Insight Workshop Academy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fellows will be engaged full-time from Monday to Friday 10 am to 4 pm in the Insight Workshop classes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B. A four-week capstone program&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the capstone project Fellows can either build from their own ideas and interests or they can be involved in one of the following Code for Nepal projects&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.asknepal.info/&quot;&gt;AskNepal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.visitjanakpur.com/&quot;&gt;Visit Janakpur&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sangraha.org/&quot;&gt;Sangraha&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nepalmap.org/&quot;&gt;NepalMap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://codefornepal.org/&quot;&gt;Code for Nepal website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Other special projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C. A Monetary reward of Nrs 5,000 after the fellow successfully completes the program.&lt;/strong&gt; (The fellowship award including the training, networking and more is worth Nrs 60,000.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning outcomes of the fellowship:&lt;br /&gt;
–&lt;/strong&gt; Leadership and communications skills&lt;br /&gt;
– Access to network with established leaders in the field&lt;br /&gt;
– Project Management: Portfolio-building with Code for Nepal and Insight Workshop**&lt;br /&gt;
–**Technical skills: Open source and web development&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deadline to Apply:  &lt;/strong&gt;March 19&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Number of Fellows for April intake:&lt;/strong&gt; 3&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;applicants-must-meet-the-following-criteria-to-apply&quot;&gt;A&lt;strong&gt;pplicants must meet the following criteria to apply:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;able to commit full-time for this Fellowship in Kathmandu&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;background in basic programming&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;identify as female&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;young professional or final year Bachelor’s student&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will call for interviews if you are shortlisted. Three fellows will work alongside the April batch of trainees of Insight Workshop Academy. To know more about the curriculum visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://insightworkshop.io/&quot;&gt;insightworkshop.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fellowship timeline:&lt;/strong&gt; April 6, 2019 to August 30,  2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You only have to fill one application form. Please fill and submit the form below by April 12.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions that have not been answered on this page, please ask using the comments section below. Also, here are &lt;a href=&quot;https://codefornepal.org/?s=hawkins+fellowship&quot;&gt;more blog posts&lt;/a&gt; related to Hawkins Fellowship including a few by our Fellows from 2019.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>codefornepal</name></author><category term="Code For Nepal" /><category term="dataviz" /><category term="Digital Literacy" /><category term="General" /><category term="scholarships" /><category term="Code for Nepal" /><category term="digital literacy" /><category term="equality" /><category term="fellowship" /><category term="nepal" /><category term="womenintech" /><summary type="html">Hawkins Fellows from the class of 2019.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">NepalMap Federal – Explore and understand Nepal using data</title><link href="/2020/02/nepalmap-federal-explore-and-understand-nepal-using-data/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="NepalMap Federal – Explore and understand Nepal using data" /><published>2020-02-24T01:41:57+00:00</published><updated>2020-02-24T01:41:57+00:00</updated><id>/2020/02/nepalmap-federal-explore-and-understand-nepal-using-data</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020/02/nepalmap-federal-explore-and-understand-nepal-using-data/">&lt;p&gt;Code for Nepal has just launched the federal version of &lt;a href=&quot;https://nepalmap.org/&quot;&gt;NepalMap&lt;/a&gt;, a web app that puts data about Nepal at your fingertips! Since 2016, this data portal has been the go-to source for many journalists, researchers, entrepreneurs and students; when they are looking for data or data visualizations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the promulgation of 2015 constitution and adoption of federal structure, we see demand for data has increased. Data users have been continuously searching for data from aligned with the new federal structure which includes 753 local bodies, 77 districts and 7 provinces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To meet the demand of users, with the help of generous support of our volunteers, we are happy to launch the federal version of NepalMap – &lt;a href=&quot;https://nepalmap.org/&quot;&gt;https://nepalmap.org/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure class=&quot;alignleft size-large is-resized&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://codefornepal.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/nepalmap-552x1024.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-2506&quot; width=&quot;534&quot; height=&quot;990&quot; srcset=&quot;https://codefornepal.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/nepalmap-552x1024.png 552w, https://codefornepal.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/nepalmap-162x300.png 162w, https://codefornepal.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/nepalmap-768x1424.png 768w, https://codefornepal.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/nepalmap-828x1536.png 828w, https://codefornepal.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/nepalmap-1105x2048.png 1105w, https://codefornepal.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/nepalmap.png 1425w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 534px) 100vw, 534px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you live in Province 1 or anywhere else in Nepal, you can find out how many people live in your Province or District or Municipality. Or find out what kind of crops or vegetables farmers produce in the area where you live. On this version of NepalMap, demographics, agriculture, educational and household data are available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NepalMap uses &lt;a href=&quot;http://nationaldata.gov.np/&quot;&gt;National Data Profile&lt;/a&gt;, created by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cbs.gov.np/&quot;&gt;Central Bureau of Statistics&lt;/a&gt;, and other official sources, to create user-friendly data visualizations on key demographic issues. You can embed, access or download the data too. You can also compare any two areas side-by-side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NepalMap is based on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Code4SA/wazimap&quot;&gt;Wazimap&lt;/a&gt; which is a fork of &lt;a href=&quot;https://censusreporter.org/&quot;&gt;Census Reporter&lt;/a&gt;. Wazimap is built and maintained by &lt;a href=&quot;http://code4sa.org/&quot;&gt;Code for South Africa&lt;/a&gt;. All of these tools are completely open source. You can build &lt;a href=&quot;https://wazimap.readthedocs.org/en/latest/index.html&quot;&gt;one&lt;/a&gt; for your country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NepalMap is entirely built by &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Code4Nepal/nepalmap_federal/graphs/contributors&quot;&gt;volunteers&lt;/a&gt; who are committed to ensuring everyone has access to open data about Nepal. We are looking for volunteers who can help us add more data, and improve NepalMap. If you have the right skills, and would like to help, please complete this &lt;a href=&quot;http://codefornepal.org/en/help/&quot;&gt;form&lt;/a&gt; or you can also directly create issues in our GitHub repo to report the bug. If you would like to access pre-federal data from 2011 Population Census, please check out: &lt;a href=&quot;https://2011.nepalmap.org/&quot;&gt;https://2011.nepalmap.org/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Code for Nepal is grateful to Clifton McIntosh for his guidance throughout the development process; Amit Chaudhary, Nitesh Rijal, Pratima Kandel, Ishan Dangol for their code contribution and Nirmal Rijal for helping us with data scraping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explore NepalMap Federal – &lt;a href=&quot;https://nepalmap.org/&quot;&gt;https://nepalmap.org/&lt;/a&gt; and feel free to write to us at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:nepalmapa@codefornepa.org&quot;&gt;nepalmap@codefornepal.org&lt;/a&gt; if you need any further information.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Nikesh Balami</name></author><category term="Code For Nepal" /><category term="dataviz" /><category term="NepalMap" /><category term="data" /><category term="Data4Nepal" /><category term="dataviz" /><category term="NepalMap" /><category term="NepalMap Federal" /><category term="Open Data" /><summary type="html">Code for Nepal has just launched the federal version of NepalMap, a web app that puts data about Nepal at your fingertips! Since 2016, this data portal has been the go-to source for many journalists, researchers, entrepreneurs and students; when they are looking for data or data visualizations.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Volunteers uploaded over 2,000 street-level imagery of Janakpur, a city in Nepal</title><link href="/2019/11/volunteers-uploaded-over-2000-street-level-imagery-of-janakpur-a-city-in-nepal/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Volunteers uploaded over 2,000 street-level imagery of Janakpur, a city in Nepal" /><published>2019-11-23T15:19:47+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-23T15:19:47+00:00</updated><id>/2019/11/volunteers-uploaded-over-2000-street-level-imagery-of-janakpur-a-city-in-nepal</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/11/volunteers-uploaded-over-2000-street-level-imagery-of-janakpur-a-city-in-nepal/">&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image is-style-default&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/L7Yvp87lqypDDd10waL9lQzp7Z-Wf3sDyjjZ8KD8JfUBG4ia05zh7zhIgy756jloWD-k7hFElbpkVFIxAB4GLIHHHt8nVWs2InicBBSNHfZaempvuOF80dYXh9FPm4J8nPejKJQU&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[November 3, 2019] Spending holiday by volunteering is fun, especially in this digital world when you can help a group of youth digitize their town. With this aim of mobilizing the local volunteers to map the street of Janakpur on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openstreetmap.org/&quot;&gt;OpenStreetMap&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&quot;https://codefornepal.org/&quot;&gt;Code for Nepal&lt;/a&gt; collaborated with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.internetmarkettoday.com/&quot;&gt;Internet Market Today&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.appantv.com.np/&quot;&gt;Appan TV&lt;/a&gt; and Smartha Nepal to organize &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/events/399271194100112&quot;&gt;2019 Digitizing Janakpur&lt;/a&gt; Workshop. It was a followup event of 2018 workshop, where we launched &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.visitjanakpur.com/?fbclid=IwAR24FeChtVJk4xb1E7hpr_ZZkrzynSNv80_iuOHgjGRHAPpy4EKoM5fomGk&quot;&gt;https://www.visitjanakpur.com/&lt;/a&gt; by mapping businesses of the city, and publishing photos and videos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the use of technology has grown, everyone now depends on online search and service. Digital content like blog posts, photos, street views, promotional videos etcetera usually appear in online search results. A town needs to have digital presence and online map so locals and tourists alike navigate the area easily. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Nepal is promoting Visit Nepal 2020 campaign, a platform like Visit Janakpur can be very useful, where the latest information about the city is contributed by local volunteers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The main aim of the 2019 digitizing workshop was: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To use Mapillary, an app, to map different routes of Janakpur key destination.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To teach young people how to become part of Google’s local guides community.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To enjoy the hands-on experience of taking 360 photos using Google Street View.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Workshop Day&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;15 volunteers gathered at Monsatic Higher Secondary School at 8:30 AM, where they received a welcome orientation from Program Coordinator of Code for Nepal, Sadikshya Karki. She shared the overall program agenda and quickly created a friendly environment within participants through warmup dance. I and Ishan Dongol accompanied her during the introduction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/ZSxJu8zvnijMZa2lC4Mtd6zGGhbAa1wqMdY0xR3xIoT4ZDvFpVaYlf1rHUHS068Kzz8zxu5_ENvlCNVqmikMv-Qtz5Hkat2y7hQzyGYyGDmNuBTRKRPJj58b6m5G0Gkcn39p5Mg8?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the short introduction session and breakfast, the participants were asked to download and setup Mapillary accounts for the mapping. Ishan Dongol lead the hands-on session to teach participants how to use Mapilary. The participants then were divided into 3 groups for the field mapping, where they visited different key places of Janakpur to collect street views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/zPG8jDHEvImkfYGOBoCbkgrfckUrNmf6zhp2RaK1atA3oUdDXDAlDvAI7SKEXhnq2u6N7Uyst73wmr9hUWAA4AOLOtavXkZlnKzXN5kwqHyOoS0ZmPRt2-URCHPuCBnWirrAQ2Z7&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After 3 hours long field visits and short lunch break, the participants went to the office premises of Internet Market Today, where the session on “How Search Works” was conducted by Amit Jha, Founder &amp;amp; CEO of Internet Market Today. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then led a short session on how to take 360 photos using Google Street View app, where I shared the importance of 360 photos and key tips of taking beautiful photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/i8IL2rN7CBV35o9eUfZLnxUvnVCrwCcjcx9oVy38WDD2h5tvF3L_GTNRUqCf4cnk7V1QuFJVBYGJ1p67xKf-_NCcGp1gcSyysqS_4A4LT6r9OClKlAuVCPDq6FXCed7LdOC8YIdQ&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The workshop was concluded by Navin Shah, Managing Director of Appan TV and Sadikshya Karki, where they encouraged participants to be connected through social media and welcomed their contribution to the Visit Janakpur portal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Outcomes of the Workshop&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Participants were able to capture the 21 street view sequences, which consists of 2575+ images of various parts of Janakpur and few 360 photos.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Nikesh Balami</name></author><category term="dataviz" /><category term="Digital Literacy" /><category term="Events" /><category term="General" /><category term="Digital Nepal" /><category term="Digitizing Janakpur" /><category term="Mapillary" /><category term="Visit Janakpur" /><category term="highlight" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Chart: Companies in Provinces of Nepal</title><link href="/2019/10/chart-companies-in-provinces-of-nepal/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chart: Companies in Provinces of Nepal" /><published>2019-10-21T00:21:21+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-21T00:21:21+00:00</updated><id>/2019/10/chart-companies-in-provinces-of-nepal</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/10/chart-companies-in-provinces-of-nepal/">&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-embed-flickr aligncenter wp-block-embed is-type-photo is-provider-flickr&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-embed__wrapper&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/bryonlippincott/41800642730/in/photolist-24EnPTi-26FMdLJ-EMfir-EMg5f-29nn4WJ&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/847/41800642730_a64a43ab22_c.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Fruit vendor waiting for customers in Kathmandu, Nepal&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Fruit vendor waiting for customers in Kathmandu, Nepal. By 

[Bryon Lippincott](https://www.flickr.com/photos/bryonlippincott/)  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The total number of companies in Nepal is 923,356. Among, them just about half (50.1%) are registered. And on average, companies in Nepal employ less than 4 people. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kathmandu, Jhapa, Rupandehi, Morang, and Sunsari are the districts with the highest number of companies in Nepal. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Province 3 has the most companies or establishments, followed by Province 1 and Province 5. Check out the chart below to see how many companies are in each province. &lt;figure&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://nada.cbs.gov.np/index.php/catalog/92&quot;&gt;Nepal Economic Census, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>codefornepal</name></author><category term="dataviz" /><category term="General" /><category term="dataviz" /><category term="nepal" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Journey at Insight Workshop through the Hawkins Fellowship</title><link href="/2019/09/my-journey-at-insight-workshop-through-the-hawkins-fellowship/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Journey at Insight Workshop through the Hawkins Fellowship" /><published>2019-09-19T06:49:33+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-19T06:49:33+00:00</updated><id>/2019/09/my-journey-at-insight-workshop-through-the-hawkins-fellowship</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/09/my-journey-at-insight-workshop-through-the-hawkins-fellowship/">&lt;p&gt;One morning I applied for an academy program in Insight Workshop (IW), a Software Company located in Naxal, Kathmandu. The deadline was just the night before. Luckily my application was counted. (Big thanks to my dearest friend Rachana for this). After a rigorous application process I was selected for the program. I also applied for this program from Hawkins Fellowship Program by Code for Nepal. I got selected as a Hawkins fellow from there too. I can’t express in words the feelings that I had that day. I was so excited and nervous about this journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone was so welcoming at IW. We were introduced with previous batch’s students, mentors and everyone else there. They shared their experiences and motivated us on the very first day. More than 50% of the trainees were girls; it was a happy feeling. I was around people with the same dreams and passion to become a future Full Stack Developer. Positive vibes were coming from everyone that we were there to learn. It was a different feeling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first month went by so fast. We learned the basics of everything from Html, CSS to Python, Django Framework. We learned how the software development process works in the real IT world. Alongside programming, we also learned problem-solving, research and time management skills. We were given assignments and challenging tasks too to boost our skills. we have to complete them by the deadlines. There were exams too. Every Friday we had guest lectures from industry experts who shared their experiences. I loved how they shared everything with us, making us feel like their own family. They wanted us to grow together and we learned so many things from every person every single day. Every single day was productive. It wasn’t hectic at all; time was feasible, the environment was co-operative and supportive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last four weeks of this academic period, we were assigned a team project based on the concepts which we had learned earlier. Although I entered as a very beginner, in just two weeks of experience and proper guidance, I was able to build a complex web application. This gave me a lot of confidence exponentially raising my passion for software development. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back to those three months, these were the most beautiful and exciting days of my life, as my career kickstarted. Currently, I am working at Insight workshop as a Software Engineer Trainee after completing these 3 months of the journey. I am so thankful for Insight Workshop as well as Code for Nepal for seeing potential in me and providing me with this opportunity. &lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sumi Prajapati</name></author><category term="dataviz" /><category term="Digital Literacy" /><category term="General" /><category term="highlight" /><summary type="html">One morning I applied for an academy program in Insight Workshop (IW), a Software Company located in Naxal, Kathmandu. The deadline was just the night before. Luckily my application was counted. (Big thanks to my dearest friend Rachana for this). After a rigorous application process I was selected for the program. I also applied for this program from Hawkins Fellowship Program by Code for Nepal. I got selected as a Hawkins fellow from there too. I can’t express in words the feelings that I had that day. I was so excited and nervous about this journey.</summary></entry></feed>